# Clay Evans

evansclay@gmail.com · (408) 348-2855

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/clay-evans</u> · Portfolio: <u>pcevans.github.io</u>

Game and interactive media developer with a wide range of experience across the development pipeline, including major work on shipped titles AVNU and Dtail. Experience in most mainstream game engines and programming languages. Passion and drive to create innovative and inspiring games.

# **SKILLS**

**Software Engineering** || PC/mobile/VR game development, build engineering, graphics development, game design, full-stack desktop/web/mobile app development, database development, socket programming, software design

*Languages* || C++, C#, Python, Lua, Verse, Java, Kotlin, Javascript, HLSL, SQL, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, bash, MIPS. IA-32

**Tools** || Unreal Engine, Unity, Roblox Studio, Unreal Engine for Fortnite (UEFN), DirectX, Visual Studio, VS Code, Xcode, Eclipse, Android Studio, Git, Perforce, Jira, Confluence, Slack, Teams

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Gameplay Engineer, Sony Immersive Music Studios**

Remote — Unreal, UEFN, Roblox, C++, Verse, Lua — November 2022 - April 2024

- Developed and aided design and production of AVNU, a Roblox platform for Sony Music artists.
- Developed game prototypes in Unreal Engine (C++), UEFN (Verse), and Roblox Studio (Lua).
- Developed and managed core linkages between games and external in-house APIs.
- Aided design, production, and publication of games and prototypes.

#### **Build Engineer, Sony Immersive Music Studios**

Remote — Unreal, TeamCity, Perforce, C++, C#, Kotlin, Python — May 2021 - November 2022

- Facilitated and developed the CI/CD and build processes for an Unreal Engine project, including:
  - Perforce command-line scripting, server maintenance, and team onboarding;
  - UnrealGameSync server maintenance, external integrations, and team onboarding; and
  - TeamCity Kotlin and Python scripting, server maintenance, and external integrations.
- Modified Unreal Engine code to strengthen the capabilities of various tools using C# and C++.
- Integrated third-party libraries for error reporting and speech synthesis into Unreal Engine projects.

#### Interactive Developer, PixelPool

Portland, OR — Unreal, C++, SQLite, Objective-C — July 2018 - May 2021

- Developed and aided design and production of Dtail, an interactive apparel merchandising application.
- Worked in a multinational Agile development team catering to top fashion retail brands worldwide.
- Interfaced with clients to steer the design and development of multiple interactive applications.
- Developed applications for Windows, iOS, GearVR, and MacOS platforms.
- Developed in the Unreal Engine using C++, Objective-C, and Blueprints with an SQLite database.
- Aided in design, developed, and implemented complex client- and customer-facing UI and UX flows.
- Created tools within the Unreal Engine and in Python, Windows batch scripts, and Docker to automate asset production processes to support the company's production team.
- Designed and implemented a cloud-based asset and data distribution system using the S3 REST API.
- Integrated third-party libraries for PDF and Excel manipulation into Unreal Engine projects.

# Workshop Facilitator, Digital Nest · Watsonville, CA — Arduino, C — May-June 2018

- Developed a curriculum for and facilitated a game development course for a youth center.

## **Teaching Assistant (x2), CSUMB** · Marina, CA — DirectX, C++, HLSL / Unity, C# — June-August 2017

- Aided students and provided educational materials for a game jam and a graphics programming class.

## Research Assistant, CSUMB · Marina, CA — DirectX, C++, HLSL— June 2016-August 2017

- Aided a graphics professor with research into voxel-based global illumination algorithms.

# **EDUCATION**

# California State University, Monterey Bay (CSUMB), Seaside, CA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science (with distinction) — December 2017

- Studied game development and general software engineering; member of the Game Research Lab.
- Game development courses mainly taught in Unity/C#.